Let's install a plugin with Webpack.
现在来安装 webpack 插件
Plugins are our way to use Webpack
插件是我们使用 webpack 完成文件转换以外操作的方式
So with loaders, we were just taking in JavaScript files,
使用加载器可以将 JavaScript 文件
and we were turning out Vanilla JavaScript files.
转换为通用的 JavaScript 文件
We were using the Babel loader to turn the ES6 that we wrote into Vanilla JS.
我们之前使用了 babel 加载器将编写的 ES6 转换为通用的 JS
But whenever we have an action that isn't just turning one file into another,
但是当我们要做的不仅仅是将一个文件转换为另一个文件时
then we need to use a plugin.
就需要使用插件
The first plugin that we're going to install is called the HTML Webpack plug-in.
我们要安装的第一个插件叫做 html-webpack-pulgin
We're starting with this plugin because it does really great things for us,
以这个插件开始 因为它在启动当前应用上
getting started in this app.
确实有很大的帮助
Also because it's a very normal plugin to install.
此外 这也是一个很常用的插件
What the HTML Webpack plugin is going to do is allow Webpack to
html-webpack-pulgin 的功能就是使 webpack
add a dynamic reference to our dist folder without us having to do it.
动态添加 dist 文件夹的引用 而无需手动操作
So a lesson or two ago,
前几节课中
when we added a hard-coded reference in the HTML to the JavaScript files,
我们在 html 中添加了引用 JavaScript 文件的硬编码
main.js, in the dist folder,
引用了 dist 文件夹中的 main.js 文件
we're not going to need that anymore.
现在不用再这样做了
We're going to instead just rely on Webpack to
只需要依靠 webpack
add the reference at the bottom of our HTML file dynamically.
就能在 html 文件底部动态添加引用
So when you go to install a plugin,
要安装插件
the first thing that you should do is actually install it into your node modules.
你要做的第一件事 实际上是将其安装到 node_modules 中
So for the HTML Webpack plugin,
对于 html-webpack-pulgin 来说
we're going to run an npm install on the HTML Webpack plugin.
就是运行这个 npm install 命令
While that's running, we're also going to go back to our Webpack config file,
在运行的同时 我们还要返回 webpack 配置文件
and we need to do some setup here to
在这里进行一些设置
actually tell that pack to use the HTML Webpack plugin.
告诉 webpack 使用 html-webpack-pulgin
The first thing that we're going to do for that is to add a reference
为此 首先要添加一个
to the HTML Webpack plugin that is living in our node modules folder now.
对 node_modules 目录中 html-webpack-pulgin 插件的引用
So we've required that plugin,
require 该插件
and we also need to tell Webpack when to run that plugin.
另外 还需要告诉 webpack 何时运行该插件
So here inside of the module.exports,
在 module.exports 里面
we're going to add a new section called plugins.
添加一个名为 plugins 的部分
Don't forget your commas.
不要忘记逗号
So in this plugin section,
在 plugins 部分
we are declaring a new instance of the HTML Webpack plugin,
声明一个 HtmlWebPackPulgin 的实例
and we're telling it to look at the HTML file in
我们告诉它查看 client/views 目录下的 html 文件
client views and to have it generate a new index HTML file for us in the dist folder.
并在 dist 文件夹中生成一个新的 index.html 文件
The cool thing about this is that now when we rerun
现在我们重新运行命令后
our command we're actually going to go back to our dist folder and see how it's changed.
返回到 dist 文件夹看看有什么变化
Here, we used to be just getting the main.js file,
这里 以前只是得到了 main.js 文件
but now we're getting two files,
但是现在有两个文件
we're getting HTML as well.
同时还生成了 html 文件
So if we take a look at this,
查看一下这个文件
now when we scroll to the very bottom of the file,
现在 滚动到文件的最底部时
we're getting this script that is bringing in the
可以看到多了一个 script 标签
main.js file from the distribution folder.
引用了分发文件夹下的 main.js 文件
What's really cool about this is,
更厉害的是
I didn't have to create it,
我不用再手动创建
I didn't even put this here.
甚至我都没有做过这个操作
The HTML Webpack plugin is doing that for us.
这些都是 html-webpack-pulgin 插件完成的
What that means is that I can go to my source index HTML
这意味着我可以转到 index.html 源文件
file and actually remove this script tag that is hard-coded,
删除这个硬编码引用 disk/main.js 的 script 标签
So here, if we were to rerun this,
简单来说 如果重新运行命令
we would just get a clean HTML file that didn't have anything at the top,
我们会得到一个干净的 html 文件 其顶部没有引用任何内容
and instead we're going to rely on this script here at the bottom.
而是在底部使用这个 script 标签
You might be asking why it's important to have
你可能会问为什么要使用这个插件来
this plugin generate the script for us instead of us just doing it ourselves.
为我们添加脚本引用而不是自己动手添加
Right now there's not a big benefit,
现在还看不出明显优势
but down the road this becomes really helpful,
但是在未来 这会很有帮助
if you ever get into slightly more advanced things like cache busting,
如果你接触到更进阶的主题 比如缓存清除
this strategy of having Webpack generate the HTML file
这种使用 webpack 生成 html 文件的策略
for you allows you to create dynamic references to certain versions of your asset files,
可以使你能创建对特定版本资源文件的动态引用
which becomes really handy.
这会非常方便
We're going to keep it installed in our project,
我们会始终将它安装在项目中
just so that as we're moving forward,
这样在后续的开发中
we don't have to worry about dynamic references.
就不用再担心动态引用
So it's just a good thing to have installed from the beginning.
所以 一开始就安装是一件好事
One last thing, because we've now decided to
最后 因为我们现在决定
use this dynamic reference to the main.js file,
使用对 main.js 文件的动态引用
something else has changed about our app that's really important to notice.
我们的应用也发生了一些其他的变化 这一点非常值得注意
It might just go by you because we haven't been paying
你可能没有意识到 因为我们还没有
a lot of attention to the server side of this application,
过多地关注应用的服务端
but a big change has happened where we're no
但是这里发生了很大的变化
longer referencing the index.html file that we are writing,
应用不再引用我们编写的 index.html 文件
instead our app is actually going to rely on the
而要开始依赖于分发文件夹中的 index.html 文件
But right now, our server doesn't know that at all.
但是现在 服务器还毫不知情
So we're going to have to go to the server folder,
所以 我们要转到 server 文件夹
and we're going to take a look at the index.js file.
看一下 index.js 文件
You can see that right now to generate the home or the root page for this application,
现在可以看到它生成了应用的主页或根页面
we are finding the client views index file.
查找的是 client/views 目录下的 index 文件
That's what Express is looking at to generate the view that we find.
这正是 Express 查找用来生成页面的文件
But now we actually don't need a reference to that file,
但是现在我们不再需要引用该文件
we need a reference to the dist index file.
需要引用的是 dist 的 index 文件
So having made this change now,
做出这个改动之后
Express knows where to find the correct version of our index html file.
Express 就知道到哪里查找正确版本的 index.html 文件了